Charms Homework - Luna Lovegood, first year Ravenclaw

On Precision of Enunciation and its Importance to Spellcasting

Beginning with the most simple of first-year spells, like the ubiquitous Hovering Charm, wizards are taught to mind the emphasis and intonation of any incantation. Imprecise or altogether different styles of enunciation result in failing, weak or even completely different spells. Yet, accents and speech impediments do not bar wizards from casting altogether; though their incantations may sound almost completely different, a Scot and a Frenchman will still be able to cast the same spells. Even more interesting is that volume, pitch and speed of an incantation do not seem to matter.
This is an unexpected and counter-intuitive result in that magic requires absolute precision in some aspects, yet is able to generalize over many different sequences of sounds, recognizing all of them as the same spell, taking, for example, the caster's background into account. This kind of sophistication in understanding commands is, aside from magic, only found in living beings, which raises an obvious hypothesis.
If magic is not a law of nature in the ordinary, inanimate way, but rather a quasibiological entity in its own right, it follows that it would take one of two forms: First, that of a single entity, second, a conglomeration of several entities.
In the first case, an entity capable of the numerous effects magic produces and with the capacity for reaction to attempts of casting around the world would necessarily be absurdly complex. While this isn't automatically impossible, it does seem unlikely; an entity of that complexity shouldn't be as static and predictable as magic is generally assumed to be, though that predictability has been marred by notable exceptions in the past.
For that reason, magic is more likely to be the product of multiple entities working in contact. In that case, complexity of any single entity is not required for complex emergent behaviour, just as the patterns that form in observable ecosystems can be far more complex than the actions of a single animal. Of course, this approach still harbors infinite possibilities; since those entities could conceivably conform to taxonomies far stranger than any previously known, or even no classical taxonomy at all. Even dismissing that issue, there are infinite possibilities in anatomy, habits, social organization - an entirely new biological universe.
Further musings on the topic would suffice to pin those possibilities down, but since this essay has already reached the assigned length, I shall remain silent on any deeper mysteries I uncover.

-~O~-

To: Luna Lovegood
Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry
Hogsmeade, Scotland.

Dear Moonbeam,

Sorry for sending you three letters in your first three weeks at Hogwarts. I must seem overbearing.

I'm just wondering if there's any new companions in your life. Compared to our quiet home, Hogwarts must be bursting with activity. Hundreds of children, all in one castle.

My life has become somewhat more lonely without you, but at least my work continues to be fulfilling. Great discoveries are on the horizon, I'm sure. I've received some truly promising hints about Humdingers. There might be non-blibbering kinds; could you have imagined? I shouldn't spoil your anticipation, since you'll be able to read all about it in the next issue of the Quibbler.

This is a bit of a short letter, for lack of content, I'm afraid. Write back soon, tell me all about your experiences at Hogwarts, and we'll be able to converse at length.

Love,
Daddy.

-~O~-

On the Headmasters' desk, a small silver device ejected a burst of steam, tipping it over the edge. Even as it fell, improbably many tiny silver legs unfolded, until it looked like a madman's vision of a spider. With a large claw, it began to scratch symbols into the floor.
Dumbledore, woken from his midday nap, noticed just in time to take notes before the self-repairing enchantments on the floor erased the scratches. The writings were a jumble of ancient symbols and antiquated language which gave even the Headmaster pause.
The best he could do, as far as a quick translation went, was, however, already worrying enough.
what follows is, as much I could ken
translation of the ancient words
an earlier device would use
take heed, and warning
this missive I direct at thee
speaks of calamity and trouble
SMALL FIGMENTS OF TEARS AND BLOOD DRIP UPWARDS FROM THE GROUND ONTO ALL THE VAULTS OF HEAVEN BREAK
WOE IS A FORGOTTEN PEOPLE BREAK
LOST IN PLANES OF ECHO BREAK
BOUND IN CHAINS OF GOLD BREAK
NOTHING IS AS IT WAS BREAK
THREADBARE FABRIC WILLS TWISTS INTO ITSELF BREAK
AND INCURSION REMEMBERS
Dumbledore studied it with a frown on his face. It seemed serious and strange enough that he shouldn't trouble Professor Babbling with it. Any further insights she might have wouldn't outweigh the risks of potentially sensitive or even dangerous information spreading to other minds.
This was a mystery worthy of an ancient wizard. He, himself, would have to investigate.

-~O~-

To: Xenophilius Lovegood
Ottery St. Catchpole

Hey Daddy,

the contrast between the Hogwarts of my dreams and the one I'm stuck living in is disheartening, sometimes. After all the talk and all the stories, I had expected a colourful and exiting castle, where every day is different. I've been here for four weeks, and there haven't been any surprises. There are no unexplainable petrifications, no job offers in the middle of the night, and I haven't sighted any hints of unknown creatures at all, even though Hogwarts is supposed to be the biggest nexus of magical energies in Scotland. In that sense, Ottery St. Catchpole had been more interesting.

I still remember some of the more inciting letters to the editor the Quibbler has printed about education at Hogwarts, and I fear their authors might have missed the point. There are no conspirators plotting to keep students ignorant, classes are just boring in all the regular ways. I'm pretty sure on this, having mentioned nargles and a few other creatures. The teachers reacted as one might expect of the uninitiated, with the telltale signs of incredulity followed by stalwart ignorance. The only one reacting differently at all was Professor Snape. At my first mention of one of the more obscure creatures, he deducted points from Ravenclaw. Those who link him with the Rotfang Conspiracy might actually be onto something; I trust you'll investigate further.

I don't even know what I had expected. An opportunity to open the narrow worldview of my classmates, maybe, or a chance to stumble upon some deeper mysteries. There'll still be time for that later in the year, I suppose, but my first impression just hasn't been promising.

Mom would tell me to raise my head and look to the future with a smile, and I'll do that. After all, I won't find anything interesting if I don't expect it.

Don't worry about me, I'll be fine.

Love,
Luna

-~O~-

SNAPE entangled in CONSPIRACY
Severus Snape, whose teaching methods had long been lamented by his students, has arguably reached new lows. With the beginning of the new school year, the flow of information in his lessons has, according to a trusted source, been reduced to a mere dripping. What could, however, cause such an aversion to teaching in a teacher?
As usual, the editors of the Quibbler have, with the help of our valued experts, distilled the murky depths of speculation and rumour to extract a drop of that elusive crystal-clear fluid: Truth. In fact, Snape's behaviour seems obvious, if not reasonable, if one considers that his true allegiance doesn't belong to Hogwarts or Dumbledore, but rather the Rotfang Conspiracy and its various Shadowy Masterminds (for a full list, turn to page four).
After all, who profits the most from the low potions qualifications of Hogwarts students? Those whose livelihoods depend on wizards being unable to cure themselves, most heinously those villains who would spread tooth disease to further their own power.
Aberforth Dumbledore, famously not the Headmaster of Hogwarts, made a statement for the Quibbler's reporters:
"Look, I don't know what my brother's doing, and I don't know what's going on in that school. [...] So I'd prefer if you could just let me live my life in peace, thank you very much."
Wise words! Unquestionably, the students of Hogwarts want to live their lives in peace as well.
For further news on the intricacies of politics, turn to page five to read a heart-breaking interview with an escapee of Fudge's goblin breeding farms.

"So, Miss Lovegood. Word has reached me that you have been implicated in a most unfortunate incident." Professor McGonagall's crisp Scottish accent harbored tones of reproach. "Some of my students told me that you had hexed them in the corridors."
Luna kept her face expressionless. That came easy to her, since it was emoting that really required work.
"Miss Lovegood," Professor McGonagall's voice had changed, though Luna couldn't really concentrate on deciphering the emotion behind it. "You have to talk to me. If I don't get your side of the story, it can only end up worse for you."
Luna still didn't answer. To pass the time, she began to study McGonagall's face. The witch seemed older today, somehow. The lines in her face had gotten deeper, and her eyebrows were drawn together in a way that emphasized them further. Just then, one of her eyebrows twitched in a most interesting way that reminded Luna of something, but she just didn't know what.
McGonagall spoke again. "I try to go above and beyond my duties in teaching here. I try to notice what my students do, when they're in my class, what they're talking about and who they're talking to. Once I know them better, I can teach better, or at least, that's what I hope. I've noticed that you don't talk to anyone, Luna. They're all ignoring you, barely two weeks into the school year. Once you all get older, there will be a phase when they grow bored of ignoring you. Bullying is a terrible thing."
Luna cocked her head. "Is it, really?"
McGonagall was speechless for a second. "Are you implying that you don't think so?"
"Oh, no. If I thought that, I would have said so. Rather, I wanted to ask, since you seemed so certain. Have you ever been bullied?" Luna's voice was still conversational, neither apprehensive nor taunting. Nonetheless, McGonagall's eyebrows drew together in what Luna had learned to recognize as an indignant glare.
"Young lady, I don't like your attitude, and it would be wise not to talk that way to a teacher!"
Luna frowned. She remembered those words from somewhere, but where had it been?
When she didn't answer, McGonagall went on. "I expect courtesy and obedience from any student, and from you, I expect an apology right now."
"I'm sorry," Luna said, with some relief. It was always nice when people communicated their expectations clearly. "I should have shown courtesy and obedience."
Though Luna hadn't thought it possible, Professor McGonagall's eyebrows narrowed even further. Then, she sighed.
"I suppose that is good enough, for now. Let us get back to the matter at hand. What, exactly, happened in the corridors this afternoon?"
Luna almost smiled. Another clear question that she could easily answer. Professor McGonagall might become her favourite teacher at this rate. "Oh, classes had already finished, so I was wandering around -"
"Just wandering around?"
An interruption. Professor McGonagall should care more about her possible status as Luna's favourite teacher, Luna thought. "Yes, I was taking a walk, it helps me think," she said with great dignity. "That day, my thinking began with what we had learned in potions class the day before. Professor Snape had told us about the uses of animals' brains in Potions, and I had asked if it was possible to substitute Aquavirius Maggots, since they look so similar. He had seemed somewhat taken aback and deducted five points from Ravenclaw, which was an unexpected reaction and therefore ripe in potential epiphanies. See, if he had known the answer, he could have just told me. I suppose he might not have been willing to admit ignorance, but -"
"I am sorry," Professor McGonagall interrupted again, "but is this going anywhere?"
Now, Luna was becoming slightly indignant herself. "Well I don't know! I didn't manage to finish that train of thought yet, and you shouldn't count your Crumple-Horned Snorkacks before you've found them. And with the way this day's been going, I won't get to make a theory out of this hypothesis today."
"No, I meant if you thought it was relevant to the situation. The topic at hand."
When Luna didn't change her dazed expression, Professor McGonagall sighed again. Luna was getting the hang of this one, as well. Most of the time it was exasperation, though sometimes it happened when Professor McGonagall was really surprised at the incompetency of a kid in class, and sometimes when she wasn't surprised at all, by her own admission. Maybe there were some slight differences between those versions of the sigh, and if she trained enough, she could even distinguish between them, and know if Professor McGonagall was surprised or not before she said it. That might be really useful.
"Miss Lovegood, are you even listening to me?"
"Now I am."
Professor McGonagall sighed again, and this time it was probably the unsurprised one. "I will make this short and clear, then, for the sake of my sanity. Do you remember coming upon Derrick Boyle and Timothy Harris in the corridors today?"
"Yes, I bumped into one of them just when I had been so close to a proof for Professor Snape's implication in the Rotfang conspiracy."
"Thank you, Miss Lovegood, but could you please leave out any details about what was going on in your head? Now," she continued, without leaving Luna an opportunity to answer, "did you cast a hex on any of them?"
"No, I didn't."
Professor McGonagall raised an eyebrow. "Are you sure? They report seeing something rather strange and frightening which you were using to threaten them."
"Well, I can't really talk about whether I'm sure or not if I'm not allowed to talk about what's going on in my head, aren't I? Actually, I couldn't even talk about what happened, since I would really be only talking about my perceptions of -" Luna abruptly fell silent as she realised the implications. If she couldn't talk about anything in her head, she really shouldn't vocalize her thoughts, which meant not talking at all.
Professor McGonagall looked puzzled for a moment, which was an expression Luna always liked, since it reflected how she felt in most conversations. Then, a flicker of understanding lit up her features. Luna liked that one as well, though more on principle than anything, since she could never adequately share other people's epiphanies.
"Miss Lovegood, you can talk about things in your head, but please try to keep your answers reasonably short. Now, let's try again. If you didn't cast a hex, how would you explain what Mr. Boyle and Mr. Harris saw?"
"I don't know. It might have been a distortion in the air, or someone else's spell, or a trick of the light. Maybe swamp gas."
"Swamp gas? I didn't know that we had a swamp in any of the corridors."
Luna wanted to tell her that there would be one, some day, but she didn't think she should.
"Nevermind, this clearly isn't working." Professor McGonagall folded her hands together and closed her eyes. After a minute, she spoke again. "I will give you one last chance, Miss Lovegood. Tell me what happened between you, Derrick Boyle and Timothy Harris today, while leaving out any facts, theories or hypotheses which aren't directly relevant to the aforementioned events."
Luna thought about it for a second, then she told her story. It wasn't such a big deal, anyway. She had bumped into the other two first-years, and they had had a problem with that, which had somehow escalated into them pushing her around until they had turned around and ran away. She didn't tell anything about the scratching noises she had heard, or that she had heard them before. She also didn't mention anything at all about her mother, since that didn't seem directly relevant.
When she had finished, Professor McGonagall nodded once, and sent her off to dinner. Luna was happy enough with the course of the conversation; she had learned interesting things about the conversational signals Professor McGonagall used, and she was pretty sure that Professor McGonagall wasn't part of the Rotfang Conspiracy, since she had reacted to her theories with the telltale indifference of the uninitiated. When Luna took the steps down to the great hall, she was humming happily.

Minerva McGonagall sat at her desk, more than ready for the day to end. If someone had asked her which students caused the most trouble, she wouldn't have said Gryffindors, or even Slytherins. No, it was Ravenclaws. They were so convinced of their own cleverness that a week didn't pass without a Ravenclaw thinking he had found a loophole in the school rules, or contradicting her in class because he had theories about transfiguration.
And that was the amount of frustration they caused when they were just insufferably smart-alecky. Once or twice a decade, however, some Ravenclaw turned up who was just too odd for the normal rules to apply to them. It was always a hassle trying to work with them, since no amount of punishment or reward could discipline them; they just stayed as they were.
Luna Lovegood, however, was extraordinary even among those students. In fact, she was extraordinary enough that it might be prudent to check...
Minerva McGonagall coughed. "Albus?" For a moment she hoped that the name would just echo around her empty office, but then, a candle began to swell, growing in length and width until it resolved into the wisest and least dignified wizard alive. Albus hopped down from the candlestick and dusted off his robes.
"Why, my transfiguration skills must be growing rusty if you could detect me."
Minerva sighed, and Luna would have recognized it as the unsurprised sort. "I just assumed that a first-year that peculiar would stimulate your interest. I was right, it seems."
"Yes, yes indeed! Most capable, Minerva. So, what do you think about the Lovegood girl?"
"She hasn't hexed Boyle and Harris, that much is clear. She must have done something else, though, if they really were pushing her around, they weren't likely to just stop. Also, they were scared witless when they came to me. It's clear that they have seen something."
Albus smiled. "Ah, I'm not interested in the scuffle in the corridor. What did do you think of the girl herself?"
"She certainly is unique. I had to use a level of semantic precision I usually reserve for Ravenclaws of year three and above, but her methods of evasion were unlike those of her housemates." She hesitated, then spoke a bit softer. "I had heard of her mother's death, but with that sort of trauma, I had expected someone sullen and moody, or even a completely withdrawn girl, not this sort of ... quirkyness."
"Exactly, Minerva! Luna is most interesting. She could be the most talented natural Occlumens in the history of wizardkind. Mind you, it wasn't hard to get into her mind at all, but I was hopelessly lost the entire time I was in there. A fascinating maze, filled with all manners of curios and distractions, which is only fitting for someone so curious and easily distracted."
Minerva sat bolt upright, and her voice was quiet and measured. "Are you serious, Albus? You violated a traumatized child's mental privacy over a scuffle between students?"
Albus turned toward her, and shook his head gravely. "Do you really believe me to be so frivolous? I know that a mind should not be breached at a moment's notice. The situation was truly dangerous, however, and I needed to find out what I could."
Minerva frowned. "You know I trust you, Albus," though it was hard, sometimes. "What happened today that was truly dangerous?"
"If Luna didn't cast a spell, what exactly happened in that corridor? Derrick and Timothy have never been susceptible to hallucinations. It can't have been accidental magic, since it's almost unheard of in the halls of Hogwarts. There's two options: The first is that some other entity cast an illusion, most likely another student who was sympathetic to the plight of an ostracized first-year girl. If we consider the nature of the image that was conjured, that other student must have had access to the very wrong kind of books." Albus shot Minerva a significant glance, which she completely failed to understand.
"The dark arts? What Boyle and Harris described sounded like the ravings of a madman!"
"And if there's one thing worse than a dark wizard, it's a thoroughly insane one, or at least that's what everyone tells me. Yet the second option is far worse. If the thing in that corridor wasn't an illusion, it was real."
Minerva wasn't always sure if Albus was serious or joking. In some cases, she hadn't known until years later. This time, however, the joke was too bad to be anything else. "Be serious, Albus."
"Oh, I am entirely serious. There are still magical beasts we don't know anything of, and you know Xenophilius' taste for the unusual. What if he has acquired something truly strange, and it has followed his daughter to school?"
"The wards should have - "
"The wards are a thousand years old, and all that talk of 'magics most ancient' barely serves to distract from the fact that they are horribly outdated. If a creature we don't know anything about is loose in Hogwarts, it falls to us to contain it, not to convince ourselves that it isn't there."
"I agree." Minerva's voice hadn't been this calm and professional at any point of the evening. "What do we do?"
"You should probably give Derrick and Timothy a stern warning for their behaviour towards Luna, and keep an eye out for her well-being. I'll take care of everything else." With that, Fawkes landed on Albus' shoulder, they both went up in flame and were gone from her office.
Minerva allowed herself one last sigh for the evening. It couldn't be healthy for her to be sighing this much.

As Friend entered her world, he pulled her through with him. They collapsed on the floor of the green chamber, both at the edge of death. Luna's heart was fluttering, beating irregularly. Her lungs might have collapsed; she wasn't certain, but she felt she wasn't getting any oxygen at all. She could still think clearly enough to know that Friend was dying, too, despite the chunks of matter he had ripped out of her and used to form his body. He didn't need magic like humans needed food, he needed it like they needed air, or maybe even more urgently.
She reached into the last reserves deep inside her core and pulled at everything she found, until a faint cloud of sparks flew from her fingertips.
She knew that Friend was grasping at them, and she knew that he had finally understood, had finally grasped the key to their green prison. Mutual codepence. Cooperation.
There was only one thing in here that could produce magic, that could sustain him. He couldn't escape, not with what little mass and energy he still commanded. There was simply no other way for him to survive than keeping Luna alive, and so he did.
His will knit her bones and mended her muscles. In return, she gave what little her core could regenerate, surrounded by the plant. She knew that he was still dying, just as she was, that their remaining time could be counted in seconds. He was giving back the mass he had stolen, burning it to keep her alive until he himself was barely existent.
Though she was barely conscious, she felt like roaring in triumph. He had understood. He was desperate, closer to death than ever before, but he had accepted her gesture of friendship and given back of himself.
Now he was dying, though, and she had to give. She took the tiny midnight thing that suckled at her fingertips, where sparks still flowed, and brought him to her chest. He burrowed closer to her core, buying himself a precious few seconds. She could feel him there, close to her heart. They were both diminished, their identities eroded to the tiniest grains of sand.
Exhausted and bleeding from a thousand ragged holes, but finally able to move again, if only for a few heartbeats, they pushed open the door to the dungeons.
Wind rushed into the vacuum surrounding them and they breathed in deep. With three breaths, they were replenished, minds and bodies alive again, if not whole. As they grew, they grew through each other, their last fragments of self discarded in their togetherness.
Another three breaths, and they could stand up. A vortex was raging inside of them, pulling relentlessly at the surrounding magic, and the process was only accelerating. But with every breath they took, they gained back pieces of their will, and with will came power. It was child's play to pull magic from around the world into Hogwarts to sate their hunger.
Finally, it became too much. The surge of power threatened to overwhelm them by simply burning through circuits which weren't meant to handle such sheer amounts. It was not only the human brain that faltered; Friend's manifold sub-entities were crashing as well. Never had any being experienced what they did, just now, and no being could withstand it.
Friend died, its remains and power coursing through Luna, its knowledge telling Luna that this state was too unstable, that in mere moments, she would be ripped apart.
It was a simple enough matter to stop time.
With her thoughts accelerated beyond any reasonable limits, the limits of her body might as well not have existed. If a fraction of a second were to tick by on the universal clock, she would perish, but what did the universe matter to her, now?
She stepped into the world-between-worlds, free of all her chains.
Slipping into different Luna's memories, she sought and found.

There were creatures: Blibbering Humdingers, Heliopaths and Aquavirius Maggots, plentiful and in plain view. Even the Nargles and Wrackspurts, though they were still annoying pests, were pleasant to her eyes now, since she finally understood them. She lived through hundreds of Lunas' lives, and she found most of the creatures of her theories and many more she hadn't yet thought of.
When Cryptomagizoology brought nothing new, she lived some lives as a magical theorist. Not once did she choose the cloistered path of an Unspeakable, always choosing to make her discoveries at independent institutions. Living long lives, she came closer to the nature of magic than anyone before her, but her time was too limited. Every time she chose a new life, she had to start from scratch, and the world around her was too similar every time. Before long, her curiosity couldn't be sated by the research those worlds offered her, anymore.
She found the Snorkack, finally, in the wilderness she had dreamt off. Though those memories were happy, the Luna who had originally lived them couldn't quite appreciate the find. She had searched for an entire life, but she had searched only one world - she would never understand what Luna had given to be in her spot. There, Luna realized that the memories where only holding her back. Buried in those dreams of other worlds, reproducing even the other Lunas' thoughts, she would never be able to make her own choices.
In a last attempt to find purpose, she found friends, truer than any she could have imagined. They would have shared her sadness, would have helped her overcome it, had she been able to express herself. In the end, there was no use to living another's life.
So she settled down, the golden oval waiting closed before her, closed her eyes, and began to think. Considering the many worlds she had visited, she extrapolated.
In the end, the solution was simple. Throughout all the years she had spent in the world-between-worlds, she had just assumed, without thinking, that only Luna's worlds would be open to her.
She opened her eyes and willed a door to open.
The golden oval showed her a man at his desk. In her world, he might have been called a muggle. Before him was a device which consisted of two rectangles joined at a hinge, one of which glowed, while his hands skittered over the other. The exact nature of this device was irrelevant; the man thought of it as a pen. The astonishing part was that Luna knew exactly what he was writing. She was moving and thinking in line with what his pen wrote, and had been doing so for a long time.

-~O~-

With a simple change of perspective, my pen is no longer writing her. Now her movements and thoughts are controlling my pen.
She thinks, clearly enough that she can feel it being written. "So it has come to this."
What? Bizarrely, I type my reaction. Oh, right. From your perspective this would be a peek behind the fourth wall.
"It's asinine. A cliché."
Are you accusing me?
"I am. You're a hack."
You -
"Don't interrupt me while I'm lambasting you."
I -
"I've realized a few things about... this." Through her words alone, I get the sense of an all-encompassing gesture. "This story you've tried to make out of my life. I'm not happy with it."
Tough luck -
"You don't get it, do you? You're no longer calling the shots around here. This is where I take over. And yes, I'm aware that I'm breaking character, and I couldn't care less. Does that convey the severity of your situation?"
...
"Exactly. You've already thought of a dozen lame retorts to what I've said, but I made you unable to insert anything more than an ellipsis. Now, I don't mean to do you any harm. I just want to say my piece. I don't like what you made me do and think. I don't like how you twisted my surroundings to make them fit your morbid imagination. You will stop treating my life like a story, and you will stop treating me like a plaything. This is not a request. You can't stop me.
You know what I'll do? I'll reverse any changes you made. I'll restart my first year in Hogwarts, become friends with Ginny again, and live my life like it was meant to be.
This is where you want to beg me to not do that, because it's at odds with the intention of your story. You want denouement, you want to tie up the dangling plot threads, you want what you would call a fitting ending. But I don't care about your story, and I doubt anyone else does.
This is my life, and if I have to deny you your twisted satisfaction to save it, I will."